#### JOSH SARNA

Pasadena, CA • joshsarna@g.ucla.edu • (262) 313-8767 github.com/joshsarna • joshsarna.github.io • linkedin.com/in/joshuasarna

## **FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

As a web developer with a physical science background, I bring to coding an analytical mindset ideal for problem solving and efficiency. I enjoy creating algorithms and incorporating mathematical tools into things I create. In my experience, software development and math both transcend disciplinary categorization. There's nothing that can't be better understood through math, and there's nothing that can't be furthered and improved by JavaScript.

**Skills:** Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, VueJS, Vuex, React, Redux, Angular.js, Node.js, TypeScript, Bootstrap, Bulma, Python, Django, Java, PHP, Wordpress, Pressable, Visual Basic .NET, HTML/CSS, SQL, Postgres, MySQL, R, MATLAB, Wolfram Mathematica, APIs, OOP, TDD, MVC Frameworks, Git, Agile, Heroku, and AWS

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Freelance Web Developer | 2018 - Present

- LawnNinja: Built a gig-booking app centered around lawn work, providing a platform through which residents can post jobs and providers can claim them, record their work, and invoice residents; this is built using PostgreSQL, Rails, React, React Native, and the Stripe API and is an ongoing Agile project
- **Backyard Organic Farms**: Built a produce delivery subscription website, the first version of which was made using Wordpress; a subsequent edition uses Rails, Vue, Postgres, and the Square API
- **Ed Sarna**: Built a personal website for a writer, using PostgreSQL, Rails, and VueJS; this includes an extensive admin interface and email notifications sent with SendGrid

# Actualize, Software Engineer & TA | 2018 - Present

- **TAship:** Teach Vue.js lessons to a live online class; assist students in developing their programming skills by providing supplementary instructional material, troubleshooting applications, and asking follow-up questions on coding techniques; grade student assignments through Github code review
- **Middle Maps:** Built an app that allows a user to search locations in Middle Earth (setting of Lord of the Rings) and to find routes between locations; learned Vue2-Filters, jsGraphics, and Heroku and wrote an efficient shortest-route algorithm in Ruby; the backend of this app is built on Rails with a PostgreSQL database, and the front-end is built on VueJS
- **Bootcamp:** Completed the three-month intensive Actualize bootcamp and learned Ruby, Rails, Javascript, VueJS, HTML, and CSS; learned how to build front-end, back-end, and full-stack apps; gained the ability to learn new frameworks and technologies quickly

# Creative Support, Supported Living Specialist | 2015 - 2018

- Supported clients with intellectual and developmental disabilities in learning Java and Python
- Modernized company system by creating online spreadsheets for tracking hours to supplement outdated paper system until payroll tracking was transitioned to a fully-computerized system

#### **OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS**

- joshsarna/**fellowship**: a ruby gem with algorithm helper-methods, including route-finding methods to minimize distance or number of steps
- joshsarna/utsless: a ruby gem that replaces `puts` statements with `p` statements at runtime
- joshsarna/red book: a ruby gem that prints random Lord of the Rings quotes to the rails server

### **EDUCATION**

University of California at Los Angeles, Bachelor of Science in Physical Chemistry | 2017

Mathematics Minor